<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<topics>
  <topic>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <major>
      <br>Welcome to the thought corner of the site!</br>
      It's pretty amazing.
      The hope is that reading will both spark some curiosity
      and that you have fun with my thoughts manifesting themselves into text.
      Taken at face-value, a lot of content will appear absurd.
      Yet we know that there is insight into the aburd anyhow.
    </major>
    <minor>Enjoy!</minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Flicker</title>
    <major>
      Our wakeful selves are in a constant tension between internal and external worlds.
      Either we examine thoughts and imagery or examine senses and scenery.
      Have you noticed when "zoned out," not noticing what is in front of you?
      Or that you tend to stare away when deep in-thought?
      With this deep thinking, we tend to look at something such as a wall or the sky.
    </major>
    <minor>
      <a href = 'https://www.nytimes.com/2016/12/29/opinion/sunday/whos-in-charge-the-body-or-the-brain.html?_r=0'>Sensory deprivation tanks</a> are amazing for showing this.
      You lose all your external and are forced into the internal.
      How comfortable are you gauging completely inwards, left alone with your thoughts?
      You should give it a try!
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Float Downstream</title>
    <major>
      Look at America.
      We see how more successful cities are ones with easy access to clean water.
      Population and prosperity of cities today rely on past discoveries of these waters.
      NYC, Chicago, Cleveland, the coastal cities...it becomes pretty obvious!
      For the same reason, the Great Plains are rather empty.
    </major>
    <minor>
      A country is shaped largely by its shape!
      History is very much geographical.
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Tetris Effect</title>
    <major>
      The phenomenon of the brain altering your experiences based on
      constant exposure to a particular activity.
      It gets its name from the effect coming from playing Tetris extensively.
      Without effort, the subject begins to see the world Tetris-like.
      Blocks become more obvious, and the person overall is ready to play, being in 'Tetris-mode'.
    </major>
    <minor>
      This is incredible information!
      <br><a href = 'https://lifehacker.com/5982005/rewire-your-brain-for-positivity-and-happiness-using-the-tetris-effect'>It can make you a happier person!</a>
      I ran into this effect after heavily playing <a><em>Borderlands</em></a>
      My visual field became more cel-shaded -- which was both bizarre and awesome!
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Burn, baby Burn</title>
    <major>
      There is no such thing as 'cold.'
      Coldness is not a 'thing' such as water or smell. It is a lack of thing.
      Rather, temperature is a measure of average molecular activity.
      So, coldness is a lack of heat, just as darkness is a lack of light.
    </major>
    <minor>
      Humans are great at 'making things from nothing'.
      Our brains are costantly searching for meaning in the world.
      We often find meaning by 'thingness.'
      Look at all the objects that we give a more lively character to.
      We call our prized possessions our babies and see faces in the clouds.
      So, we are always interpreting -- all the time, every minute.
      Now, is that person truly angry at us? Was that event truly a miracle?

      Also, bark at your roommates or your parents: you <em>never</em> 'let the cold in.'
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Eat Up</title>
    <major>
      Eating is theft.
      When we eat, we steal energy.
      Particularly, we steal energy from a once-living thing.
      Whether that's the sugar, meat, or leaves of life.
      We do not charge ourselves from a outlet or from a gas tank. We get nutrition from eating never-living objects.
      Our fuel is bio-degradable.
    </major>
    <minor>
      The circle of life is all around us!
      If we want to go further, no life is possible without the sun.
      So, the energy spent reading this was basically solar energy!
      Praise the Sun ☼
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>How Attractive</title>
    <major>
      Gravitational pull is not only for heavier objects.
      We see this misconception everywhere!
      Not only does everything have a gravitational pull,
      everything pulls everything else!
    </major>
    <minor>
      Granted, we only see this pull from larger objects.
      Yet I pull you and you pull me.
      All chairs in a room pull on each other to the smallest degree. Gravity -- it's for everything to enjoy!
      Maybe the hippies were right about the oceanic connectedness of the universe.
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Losing my Direction</title>
    <major>
      Maps are equally correct when they are upside-down.
      There is no universal law stating what is proper orientation.
      You will find yourself from point A to B without much hassle.
    </major>
    <minor>
      Of course, we orient maps to convention -- specifically to Earth's poles.
      Conventions are incredibly useful. They keep life orderly.
      Sometimes, we give them a bit too much credit.
      Maps, serving sizes, what is fashionable, what makes a successful life.
      What is right often seems to people what is convention.
      How authentic do we allow our thoughts to be?
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>It's All Relative</title>
    <major>
      E = mc^2 is not the full equation. It is actually E^2 = (pc^2)^2 + (mc^2)^2.  When an object is said to be at rest, its momenetum is 0, so p = mass*velocity = 0, leaving us with E^2 = (mc^2)^2. Square-root each side, then you arrive at E[rest] = mc^2.
    </major>
    <minor>
       Einstein’s famous equation is Pythagoras’ Theorem at play.
    </minor>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <title>Physica</title>
    <major>
      Standard physicalism is the belief that everything is reducible to the physical world.
      This includes life. After all, our psychology relies on our biology, which relies on chemistry, which relies on physics. So, we are physical. This means all emotions, beliefs, and personalities are fundamentally physical. All that you love is physical.
    </major>
    <minor>
      So what?
      Granted the laws of physics, we see how the world is determinable.
      We know that, if we crunch the numbers right, we can launch a soccer ball so many yards.
      All physical activity is then a computation for us to discover, all set-in-stone.
      If that's the case, how much freedom can you and I have?
      On this view, humans are no more than a soccer ball.
    </minor>
  </topic>
</topics>
